I can't believe my little brother's married!
天啊，不敢相信我小弟結婚了
Why didn't you tell me you were eloping?
你們決定私訂終身 怎麼沒跟我說？
Well,we were at court, eating lunch
一切都發生得很自然 我們在法院吃中飯
Why were you at the courthouse?
等等，你們幹嘛去法院？
We were having lunch.
吃中飯啊
We were like...
那時的感覺就像是…
...we're here,we're having lunch. Let's get married! Right?
既然都來法院吃中飯了 不如就順便結婚吧
A year ago,I didn't know I had a brother. Now I have a sister!
一年前我還不知道自己有弟弟 現在又多了個妹妹
Oh,it's so great.
真是太棒了
Okay.
好了
夠了
Stop it! Don't!
別再親了
I'll get you a gift now.
我得送你們新婚禮物才行
Is there anything you need?
你們有需要什麼嗎？
We've been trying to get pregnant since we got engaged,to get a jump on things.
我們訂婚後就一直想懷孕 心想越早生越好
No one's getting any younger.
總是年輕不再了嘛
Because the thing is,we're not able to,you know,conceive.
不過重點是我們沒辦法… 成功做人
We've seen a bunch of doctors.
我們試過所有方法 看了一堆醫生
They say that our only chance to have a baby...
對，他們說我們若想生小孩
...is that if they take my sperm, her egg,put it together in a dish...
唯有把我的精子和她的卵子 放進培養皿裡頭
...and put it into another girl.
再放進另一個女孩的子宮裡
We were wondering if you could be that girl.
不知道你願不願意 讓我們把受精卵放進去？
That's a really nice gift.
這真是個很棒的禮物
I was thinking of a gravy boat.
我還以為 你們會想要個是醬料皿呢
We know it's a lot to ask.
我們知道這個要求很過份
We don't have anyone else to go to. We could pay someone...
但我們求助無門 本想找別人做代理孕母
...but we don't have that kind of money.
但我們沒那筆錢
Plus,you know,you're family and,you know...
再加上你又是家人
...I just don't want my baby to grow into some chick I don't know,you know?
我也不想把孩子 放進不認識的女孩肚子裡
Don't give us an answer yet, think about it.
不急著回答，你考慮看看
And if you say no, we'll totally understand.
若你拒絕，我們也能完全瞭解
Okay. Okay.
好吧…
And we were wondering if you could give us a ride down to the train station.
對，能不能載我們去火車站？
Well,actually,we kind of need an answer to that one right now.
這問題可能要馬上回答才行
The One with Phoebe's Uterus
菲比的子宮
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Check it out! Guess what job I just got.
大伙照過來 猜我得到了什麼工作？
I don't know,but Donald Trump wants his blue blazer black.
不知道，但是唐納川普 想把他的藍色外套黑回去
What?
什麼？
Blue blazer back. He wants it back.
把藍色外套要回去，是要回去
You said "black." Why would he want his blue blazer black?
你剛才是說「黑」 他把藍外套黑回去幹嘛？
Well,you know what I meant.
你知道我的意思
You messed it up.
是你說錯了
You're stupid.
你真蠢
So,what job did you get?
喬伊，你是得到什麼工作？
Tour guide at the museum. Ross got it for me.
在博物館當導覽員 羅斯幫我爭取到的
Don't you have to be a dinosaur expert?
在博物館當導覽員 不是得要恐龍專家才行？
They give you all the information.
不盡然，他們會把資料都給你
It's like memorizing a script.
就跟背劇本一樣
On your left you have a tyrannosaurus rex, from the Jurassic Period.
左方是侏羅紀的暴龍
Very nice.
不賴嘛
Yeah,actually,Joey, it's the Cretaceous Period.
其實暴龍是白堊紀的恐龍
But I can pronounce Jurassic.
是，但我念得出侏羅紀
Frank Jr. and Alice got married!
你們猜怎麼著？ 法蘭克和艾莉絲結婚了
Oh,my God!
天啊
They're having a baby!
而且他們就要生小孩了
They want me to grow it for them in my uterus!
而且他們還要用我的子宮來生
-My God! -Are you serious?
天啊 你是認真的嗎？
You're thinking of having sex with your brother?
你在考慮和自己的弟弟上床？
Ew! And,oh,no!
噁心喔，才不是
They want me to be the surrogate.
他們只是要找我當代理孕母
It's her egg and his sperm. I'm the oven. It's their bun.
用他們的精子和卵子 我只負責當爐子烤麵包
What did you say?
那你答應了沒？
I had to think about it first, but what is there to think of?
他們說要先讓我考慮一下 但是有啥好考慮的？
I'll be giving someone the greatest gift.
這是我能送出最重的厚禮
You'll carry their child and get them a Sony PlayStation?
你幫他們生小孩 還加贈新力PS遊戲機？
This is an incredible thing to do.
這對他們一定是意義重大
But there are things to think about.
但是你得考慮到一些事
Yeah,you'd be pregnant. I mean,pregnant.
對啊，你會懷孕，懷孕耶
I know.
我知道啊
You'll put your body through an awful lot.
這對身體可是沉重負擔
I mean,morning sickness,labor.
會害喜，還有分娩
It's all for somebody else.
還全都是為了別人
Yeah. What's your point?
是啊，你的重點是什麼？
Well,the stuff I just mentioned.
我剛才說的就是啊
I couldn't do that.
這種事我一定做不到
I always figured the first time I had a baby, it'd be with someone I love.
我心想自己第一次懷孕 一定會是跟心愛的人
And that baby was,you know...
孩子出生之後…
...a keeper.
一定要留在自己身邊
You were more supportive when I wanted to make denim furniture.
我當時要用牛仔布做傢俱時 你們都還比較支持
If you decide to do this, we'll be supportive like crazy.
如果你決定要這麼做 我們一定支持得五體投地
Just think it through.
我們只是要你考慮清楚
Talk to somebody who's had a baby. Like your mom.
或許和生過小孩的人討論一下 好比你母親
My mom never gave birth. Oh! But my birth mom did!
我媽才沒生過小孩呢 不過我的生母有
（中央咖啡館）
I love this tushy! Can I take it to work with me?
我喜歡你的小屁屁 可以讓我帶去上班嗎？
Yeah,sure. It's not mine anyway. It came with the pants.
沒問題，反正不是我的 是買褲子附贈的
I am so jealous.
我嫉妒死了
You guys are just right there.
你們倆真的好投入
Yes.
是啊
Right where?
投入什麼？
The beginning,where it's all sex and talking...
剛開始的熱戀啊 上床、聊天…
...and sex and talking.
再上床、再聊天
You got to love the talking.
聊天的部分很棒
-And the sex? -We haven't had sex.
那上床呢？
我們還沒上過床
What's the big deal? This is special.
有啥好大驚小怪的？ 這樣才特別啊
I want our love to grow before moving to the next level.
在進入下一個階段前 我要讓愛情先滋長
Oh,Chandler,that is so nice.
錢德，這真的太棒了
That is really nice...
真的是很棒
...Iying!
騙人！
-No way is that the reason. -Why?
不可能會是那個原因 為什麼？
Because you're not mature enough to understand that?
因為你太幼稚 無法瞭解那種事？
He's right. I'm totally lying.
不，羅斯說的對，我是在騙人
Then what is it?
那真相是什麼？
Kathy's last boyfriend was Joey.
因為凱茜前任男友是喬伊
And you're afraid you won't be able to fill his shoes?
你擔心自己…技不如人？
I'm afraid I won't make love as well as him.
不 我擔心自己床上功夫沒他行
-I was going for the metaphor. -I was saying the actual words.
我是想要用比喻的 我是直接說出來
He's had a lot of girlfriends. Doesn't mean he's great in bed.
沒事啦，喬伊交過一卡車女友 這也不表示他床功一流
We share a wall.
我和他的臥房只隔了一道牆
Either he's great,or she liked to agree with him a lot.
若非他真的很強 就是他女友喜歡附和他
Loudly and a lot.
動不動就大聲附和
All night long she'd agree.
從半夜附和到天亮
It'll be different. The sex will be great because you're in love.
你們的情況不一樣 有愛做基礎的性會更棒
-Just go for it. -Yeah,you should.
是嗎？ 是啊 錢德，放手一試吧
All right. I'll sleep with my girlfriend.
好吧，我去跟女友一起睡
But I'm just doing it for you guys.
但我這全是為了你們
Now,the mastodon is from the semi-late Jurassic Period.
乳齒象來自侏羅紀半晚期
Isn't the mastodon from the Pliocene Epoch?
乳齒象不是上新世的嗎？
This is a museum. No talking.
這裡是博物館，不能說話
Right down here we have...
這裡的就是…
...a large foot.
大腳
And over here we have Ross Geller.
這位是羅斯蓋勒
Everyone wave "hi" to Ross.
大家揮手和羅斯打招呼
Ross is one of our scientists. Look at him hard at work.
羅斯是館內頭號重要的科學家 你們看他工作有多努力
Okay,moving right along.
好，繼續參觀
Come on.
走吧
It's open. Come in.
門沒關，請進
-I'm sorry I'm late. -That's okay.
抱歉遲到了 沒關係
I had time to finish glazing my nipples.
我正好有時間替乳頭上釉
You go all out when you're expecting company.
你為了見客還真是拚命
I was working on my pottery.
我說的是陶器
Oh! I didn't know that you did pot.
我不知道你會做…鍋子
Mostly nudes. It combines my two passions: pottery and erotica.
對，大多沒穿衣服 結合陶藝和色情這兩種愛好
Erottery!
就叫做「陶情」吧
Thanks for coming out to see me.
謝謝你來看我
I thought it'd be a good idea to talk about this baby stuff in person.
我只是覺得生小孩這件事 還是當面聊比較好
I don't think it's a good idea.
菲比，我覺得這樣不妥
Why not?
為什麼？
You'd be giving up a baby.
因為你最後得要送走孩子
And I really don't
我不知道…
I don't know if anything I said...
不知道要怎麼說...
...would make you understand the pain of giving up a baby.
...你才會懂 送走孩子會有多麼痛苦
所以…
No,no,I understand the pain. Don't hurt the puppy!
不…我瞭解那種痛苦 不要傷害小狗
No,no. The puppy is yours.
不是啦…這小狗是你的了
-I get a puppy? -But for only three days.
我有小狗？ 對，但只能擁有三天
Why?
為什麼？
I realize I don't have any right to start getting parent-y on you now.
我知道我現在沒有權力 突然搬出媽媽的臉孔跟你說教
Look at me and not the puppy. It's very important.
菲比，麻煩別看小狗 看著我，我要說重要的事
I know what I'm talking about.
我知道我在說什麼
I gave up two babies.
我送走過兩個孩子
I only wish I had someone who'd given up babies that told me...
只希望當時能有前輩告訴我
...how terrible it is.
送走自己的小孩會有多痛苦
I really shouldn't have given you the puppy first.
早知道就別先把小狗給你
That's okay. No,we're listening.
沒關係，我專心聽你說
It'd be something you'd regret every day for the rest of your life.
我只是覺得送走孩子後 你會每天後悔直到死掉
So however hard it is for you to give up this puppy...
你到時送走這條小狗的痛苦
...it'd be a million times harder to give up a child.
還不及送走孩子的百萬分之一
Okay,fair enough. Three days.
好，很合理，就養三天
Oh,it's time to take my ass out of the kiln.
該把屁股拿出烤窯了
Could you sit there? I'm saving this seat for my friend Ross.
你能不能坐對面？ 我幫朋友羅斯留了位置
You mean Dr. Geller?
你是說蓋勒博士？
Doctor? I didn't know he had a nickname.
博士？我不知道他有這綽號
Oh,he won't sit here.
他才不會坐這裡呢
Only people in white coats sit there.
穿白袍的都會坐在那裡
Only people in blue blazers sit here.
穿藍色外套的只能坐這裡
-How come? -That's just the way it is.
為什麼這樣？ 就是這樣
That's crazy.
豈有此理
Maybe it's crazy in a perfect world: a world without lab coats and blazers.
或許在不分藍白的完美世界裡 這樣就會是豈有此理
But you not in a perfect world. You in a museum now.
但你不是活在完美世界 而且這裡是博物館
See that scientist?
看到那戴眼鏡的科學家沒？
He and I used to play together in grade school,but now....
想當年我們念小學還是玩伴 但現在呢？
Peter! Hey,Peter!
彼德！…
It's me! Rhonda,from P.S. 129?
我是朗妲，我們是同屆的啊
I shared my pudding with you,man!
虧我把布丁分你吃過
I gave you my Snack Pack!
我還把點心棒送給你吃
See? He pretend he don't even hear me!
看到沒？他假裝通通沒聽到
Everyone's pretending they don't hear you.
我想大家都在假裝沒聽到
I don't know about your jackets and separate tables...
我是不知道什麼制服 還有你們分桌吃飯的事啦
...but Ross is my friend.
不過羅斯是我的死黨
And if I save him a seat, he will sit in it.
若我幫他留了位置 我告訴你，他一定會坐
Here! I saved you a seat!
羅斯…來這裡坐 我幫你留了位置
I'm cool here. I'll catch up with you later.
我坐這裡就好了 之後再去找你聊
This is saved.
這個位置有人坐了
Gift shop.
她是禮品店的
I'm really,really sorry about what happened in the cafeteria today.
今天在自助餐廳的事很抱歉
You do what you got to do.
沒什麼，該怎麼做就怎麼做
The scientists and the tour guides never sit together.
不只是我而已 科學家和導覽員從來不坐一起
Whatever.
隨便啦
It's like that everywhere. Mon,back me up.
這種情況到處都有 摩妮卡，幫我說說話啊
Where you work,the waiters eat with the waiters.
在你工作的地方 侍者和侍者一起吃飯
And the chefs eat with the other chefs?
廚師和廚師吃飯，對吧？
I eat by myself in the alley, because everybody hates me.
我是自己躲在巷子裡吃 因為大家都恨我
Okay,Rach,when was the last time you had lunch with the shipping clerks?
好，瑞秋，你上回 和運貨員一起吃飯是何時？
I've never had lunch with the shipping clerks...
你聽我說，我不常跟他們吃飯
...but it's totally different. They're not allowed in the executive cafeteria.
但這完全是兩碼子事 因他們不能進主管的自助餐廳
Oh,I see what you're saying.
我懂你的意思了
Look,Ross.
羅斯，你聽我說
It's no big deal.
這沒啥大不了的啦
You wear a white coat. I wear a blue blazer.
你穿白袍，我穿藍色外套
If that means we can't be friends at work,so be it.
若這表示我們上班不能當朋友 那就這樣吧
I understand,you know?
我能瞭解
When I'm in a play and you're in the audience,I don't talk to you.
我演舞台劇，你坐觀眾席 我也不會跟你說話，是吧？
So it's,you know,it's cool.
所以沒事了
I'll see you tomorrow.
明天見
When we're in the audience, he doesn't talk but he does wave.
我們坐在觀眾席 他是沒說話，但有跟我們招手
Who's my puppy? Who's my puppy? Who's my puppy?
我的小狗好不好呀？…
-Have you named him yet? -No,I don't want to get attached.
你幫它取名字沒？ 沒有，我不想陷下去
-Can I hold him? -Sure. Here.
可以讓我抱抱嗎？ 當然可以
-Come here,squirmy. Hello -Not like that. No.
來，給我抱抱 不是那樣抱啦
Why's Phoebe singing to Karl Malden?
菲比幹嘛唱歌給卡爾馬登聽？
I think it's time for puppy to go out again.
小狗又應該出去了
Come on,let's go to the balcony.
走，我們去陽台
The street. Come on,let's go to the street.
什麼？ 去街上，走，我們去街上
Don't go on the balcony until after I get back.
在我回來之前，別去陽台
So did you do it?
你們做了沒？
Yes,yes,we had the sex.
有…我們上床了
It was bad?
糟糕，不好喔？
It was fine,but she didn't agree with me as strongly as with Joey.
好是好，但是她附和我的程度 不像附和喬伊那樣強烈
She was like,"l see your point. I'm all right with it."
感覺像是「我瞭解，無所謂」
There's not always a lot of agreement the first time.
第一次的互動總是比較生疏
Yeah. Not for girls,anyway. Guys agree like that.
對，女生要慢慢來 不像男生一碰就互動了
Look,you have to help me.
你們得幫幫我
I mean....
我是說…
I know what to do with a woman. It's always nice.
我知道怎麼在床上取悅女人 我知道步驟，一直也都很好
I need to know...
但我需要知道…
...what makes it go from nice to:
要怎麼從「好」進階到…
"My God! Somebody's killing her in there!"
「老天 那傢伙讓她欲仙欲死」
I'll show you something a lot of guys don't know.
我來開釋一個 很多男人不知道的事
瑞秋，麻煩把那本子給我
All right.
好吧
Now.
來羅
You don't have to draw an actual Whoa,she's hot!
你不用真的畫出… 哇，她身材真惹火
Everyone knows the erogenous zones.
大家都知道性感帶在哪裡
You got one,two,three...
有一、二、三…
...four...
四…
...five,six and seven.
五、六，還有七
There are seven?
性感帶有七個？
Let me see that.
我看看
Oh,yeah.
對，沒錯
That's one?
那裡也算一個？
Kind of an important one.
還蠻重要的呢
I was looking at it upside down.
反過來看會有誤差嘛
Well,you know,sometimes that helps.
有時候反過來也不錯
Most guys will hit one,two,three and then go to seven and set up camp.
男人大多數愛撫過一、二、三 就直接跳到第七個，結束比賽
That's bad?
那樣不好嗎？
At Disneyland,you don't spend the whole day on the Matterhorn.
你去迪士尼樂園 也不會整天只玩馬特洪雪橇啊
You might if it were like seven.
若那是第七個就有可能
All right,the important thing is to take your time.
重點是慢慢來
You want to hit them all...
七個性感帶都要照顧到
...mix them up. Keep them on their toes.
還要搭配混和使用 就像踮腳那樣維持緊繃
Oh,toes!
腳趾！
For some people.
有些人的腳趾會興奮嘛
All right.
好吧
You could start out with a little one.
你可以先小小來個一
A two.
再來二
A one,two,three.
一、二、三搭配
A three.
一個三
A five.
一個五
A four.
一個四
A three,two.
來個三和二
Two. A two,four,six.
二，再配個二、四、六
Two,four,six.
二、四、六
Four. Two.
四、二
Two. Four,seven!
二，四和七
Five,seven! Six,seven!
五配七，六配七
Seven! Seven!
七！…
Seven! Seven! Seven! Seven! Seven! Seven!
Seven!
And there you are.
這樣就可以了
Yeah,that'll work.
對，那樣會有效的
Dr. Geller? There's a seat here.
蓋勒博士，這裡有位置
Thank you,Dr. Phillips.
菲利普斯博士，謝謝你
But I'm having my lunch...
但我的午餐…
...at this table. Here in the middle.
要在這張桌子上吃 中間這一張
I'm having my lunch...
我的午餐…
...right here with my good friend,Joey.
就在這裡和好友喬伊一起吃
If he'll sit with me.
若他願意跟我坐一起的話
I will sit with you,Dr. Geller.
蓋勒博士，我跟你坐
You know...
你們知道嗎…
...we work in a museum of natural history.
我們在自然史博物館工作
And yet,there is something...
然而卻有一件事…
...unnatural...
很不自然
...about the way we eat lunch.
我們吃中飯的方式很不自然
Now,I want you to know...
我要讓你們知道
...it took a tour guide to show this scientist the error of his ways.
這位導覽員讓我這科學家 瞭解到自己處事方法的錯誤
You might even say he took me on a tour...
甚至可以說他帶領我 看到了...
...of myself.
...我自己的內心
Yeah,that was me.
對，他說的就是我
I look around,and you know what I see? I see division.
我環顧這自助餐聽的四周 看到了什麼？我看到隔閡
Division between people in white coats and people in blue blazers.
穿白袍的人和穿藍外套的人 彼此有著隔閡
I ask myself,"My God,why?"
我捫心自問 「天啊，這是為什麼？」
Now,I say we shed these coats...
我建議大家脫掉…
...that separate us.
造成我們隔閡的這些外套
And we get to know the people underneath.
才能認識衣服裡面的人
I'm Ross!
我是羅斯！
I'm divorced and I have a kid!
我離過婚，有個小孩
I'm Joey! I'm an actor!
我是喬伊，我是個演員
I don't know squat about dinosaurs!
我對恐龍一竅不通
I'm Ted,and I just moved here, and New York really scares me.
我是泰德，一個月前才搬來 紐約真是嚇壞我了
-There you go! -Hang in there,Teddy!
這就對了！ 泰德，你要撐住
I'm Andrew.
我是安德魯
And I didn't pay for this pear.
這顆西洋梨我沒付錢
Okay. Good for you.
好，有你的
I'm Rhonda! And these aren't real!
我是朗妲，這一對不是真的！
Wow,Rhonda.
朗妲…
-I'm Scott. -Yeah,okay,Scott!
我是史考特 幫史考特加油
I flip the light switch on and off 17 times when I leave a room...
我在離開一個房間之前 一定要連續開燈關燈17次
...or my family will die.
不然我全家都會死光光
My mom's gonna be here any minute.
我媽隨時會來
I can't. I can't give him up.
我沒辦法，我不能送走它
Yes,no. I can.
不對，我可以
I don't want to.
我不想
But I can.
但是我可以
No.
不行
I can't watch this. It's like Sophie's Choice.
我再看下去一定會崩潰 這就像是「蘇菲的選擇」
You know,I never saw that.
我從沒看過那部電影
Oh,it was only okay.
其實很普通而已啦
I can't do this.
我辦不到
My mom was right. If I can't give him up...
我媽媽說的對 若我連一條狗都捨不得
...there's no way I can give up a baby.
怎麼可能送走自己生的小孩
Frank and Alice are going to be so crushed.
法蘭克和艾莉絲一定會很受傷
What else can I give them? A kidney!
我能給他什麼別的？腎臟？
We were in the neighborhood.
我們正好在附近
We want to let you know that there's still no pressure.
我們順路過來是要讓你知道 還是不要有壓力
If there was something you wanted to say,we'll be right there.
但是如果你有事要跟我們說 我們就坐在那裡喝咖啡
Who's this little guy?
這個小傢伙是誰？
He's so cute! He reminds me of my old dog,Tumor.
真可愛 讓我想起我的老狗腫瘤
You are so precious, I could take you home.
瞧你可愛的，真想帶你回家
Why don't you?
有何不可呢？
-Are you serious? -Yeah.
你是說真的？ 是啊
Thanks.
多謝了
-What are you doing? -I'm okay with this.
你在幹嘛？ 這樣不會讓我難過
You know why? Because look at them.
你們知道原因嗎？看看他們
Look how happy they are.
看他們高興成那樣
And I made that,so you know....
這是我的功勞，所以…
It'll be a million times harder to give up a baby,but oh,my God!
我知道送走自己生出來的孩子 一定會難上百萬倍…
It'll feel a million times better,right?
但到時的快樂 一定也會是百萬倍，對吧？
I'll do this. I want to carry your baby.
決定了，我要懷你們的孩子
Thank you so much!
真是太感謝了
You don't know what this means to us.
這對我們意義非凡
I think I'm going to cry!
天啊，我都快哭了
It's going to be so great.
一定會很棒的
-What's going on? -I gave them the puppy.
怎麼回事？ 我把小狗給了他們
It made them so happy, I decided to carry their baby.
看他們高興成那樣 我決定幫他們懷小孩
-Phoebe -No,I know.
菲比… 你不用說，我知道
We're different,though.
不過你我是完全不同的人
This is a different situation.
而且情況也完全不同
I am not going to regret this.
我知道我這樣做絕不會後悔
I understand all that.
你說的我都瞭解
It's just,that was my puppy.
只是…那小狗是我的耶
Would you ever be a surrogate?
你願意幫別人當代理孕母嗎？
Depends who asked.
要看是誰要我幫忙
What if I asked?
如果是我要你幫忙呢？
Oh,Mon,sure!
摩妮卡，那我當然願意啊
-Really? -Yes.
真的？ 是啊
You're not asking me,are you?
你不是真要我幫忙吧？
-No. -Yes. Totally.
不是 我當然幫你，一定幫
Thank you! Thank you!
謝謝你…
Thank you! Yes,thank you!
謝謝你 太謝謝你了！